# **Elliot Himmelfarb**

Quick Learning, Full-Stack Javascript Developer out to change the world. My Passions are learning, building, and self-improvement.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Arduino Mood Chat App** — *Angular, SocketlO, IBM Watson*

https://github.com/eileenzhong/third-hackathon

Hackathon Project - Sends messages through IBM Watson's Tone Analyzer and colors an Arduino LED accordingly.

#### **Yelp off Yelp** — MEAN stack, User Auth, Yelp API

https://github.com/elliothimmelfarb/yelp-business-search-tracker

Search Yelp.com. Save and remove favorites. See how many times a business has been favorited by others.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Coding House**

— Code Mentor

Pleasanton, CA | July 2016 - PRESENT

- Reviewing code and assisting students
- Building production grade apps with individually and in teams
- Studying CS concepts and learning new frameworks and skills

# Ewha Little Campus, Ulsan MapleBear Canadian Immersion School, Seoul

#### — Foreign English Teacher

South Korea | March 2014 - March 2016

- Taught lessons with self-created material
- Fast paced, high intensity environment
- Interfaced with parents and Korean culture as a foreigner.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Coding House** — Full-Stack Javascript Development

Fremont, CA | June 2016 - August 2016

# **University of Oregon** — B.A Cultural and Archaeological Anthropology

Eugene, OR | August 2009 - July 2013

2915 Baseline Rd, Unit 514

Boulder, CO 80308

(626) 639-5973

### ellioth@futurecode.ninja

http://futurecode.ninja/

https://github.com/elliothimmelfarb

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliot-himmelfarb-1434797

#### **Proficient**

ES6

Angular

Node

**Express** 

MongoDB

Mongoose

**MEAN Stack** 

Google Maps API's

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap3

Pug/Jade

iQuery

Gulp

Websockets

REST

APIs

Airbnb's Style Guides

John Papa's Angular 1 Style Guide

#### **Exposure**

React

Redux

Flux

Mocha

AWS S3

Firebase

Chai

IBM Watson

Unity

Java

Python

C++

MySQL

TDD